RG 004:118, Ridgefield Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Ridgefield Probate Court records
1841-1975
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Ridgefield District)
102 cubic feet
Record books, 1841-1941; Probate files, 1841-1975.
RG004_118
2011-071 nad 2011-072
Historical Note
Ridgefield, Fairfield County, Town settled 1708, established in October 1709
The Ridgefield Probate District was constituted June 10, 1841, from the Danbury Probate District. The Ridgefield Probate District merged with the Bethel, Newtown, and Redding Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Northern Fairfield County Probate District which serves the municipalities of Bethel, Newtown, Redding and Ridgefield.
Town of Ridgefield, Probate District chronology:
October 1709 - May 1728, Fairfield District
May 1728 - October 1746, Stamford District
October 1746 - June 9, 1841, Danbury District
June 10, 1841 - January 4, 2011, Ridgefield District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Northern Fairfield County District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-14, 1841-1921. Contact the probate court to access original record books after Volume 14. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1841-1975. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered from 1 to 14. Some volume numbers repeat or have a letter after the number, i.e., "1A".
Probate files in accession 2011-072 are arranged by file number.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-072.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Ridgefield
Places:
Ridgefield (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files dated 1921 or later are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Accession 2011-071, Record books, 1841-1941; and Accession 2011-072, Probate files, 1841-1975, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-12, 1841-1916, were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The record books were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on December 20, 2010.
The probate files were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on December 20, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1841-1941; 15 cubic feet (28 volumes); 2011-071
  - Index to Ridgefield probate records
  - Records, 1841-1856 (Volume 1A)
  - Records, 1856-1941 (Volume 1B)
  - Bonds, 1871-1911 (Volume 1C)
  - Bonds, 1909-1940 (Volume 2)
  - Guardians and trustees, 1869-1913 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1854-1865 (Volume 2A)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Guardians & minors, 1865-1911 (Volume 2B)
  - Records, 1867-1880 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1854-1884 (Volume 4A)
  - Testate estates, 1880-1888 (Volume 4B)
  - Records, 1853-1907 (Volume 5A)
  - Records, 1888-1892 (Volume 5B)
  - Records, 1892-1895 (Volume 6)
  - Orders, 1883-1886 (Volume 6A)
  - Testate & intestate estates, 1885-1906 (Volume 6B)
  - Testate & intestate estates, 1885-1906 (Volume 7A)
  - Records, 1896-1900 (Volume 7B)
  - Records, 1904-1913 (Volume 8A)
  - Testate & intestate estates, 1882-1901 (Volume 8B)
  - Records, 1902-1905 (Volume 9)
  - Orders and decrees, 1911-1920 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1905-1908 (Volume 10)
  - Orders and decrees, 1918-1924 (Volume 10A)
  - Records, 1909-1912 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1912-1917 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1917-1919 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1919-1921 (Volume 14)
- Probate files, 1841-1975; 87 cubic feet; 2011-072
  - 1 - 75 (Box 1)
  - 76 - 180 (Box 2)
  - 181 - 244 (Box 3)
  - 245 - 324 (Box 4)
  - 325 - 405 (Box 5)
  - 407 - 476 (Box 6)
  - 477 - 564 (Box 7)
  - 565 - 627 (Box 8)
  - 628 - 693 (Box 9)
  - 694 - 770 (Box 10)
  - 771 - 851 (Box 11)
  - 852 - 930 (Box 12)
  - 931 - 996 (Box 13)
  - 997 - 1082 (Box 14)
  - 1083 - 1165 (Box 15)
  - 1166 - 1247 (Box 16)
  - 1248 - 1321 (Box 17)
  - 1322 - 1433 (Box 18)
  - 1434 - 1614 (Box 19)
  - 1615 - A1662 (Box 20)
  - A1663 - A1670 (Box 21)
  - A1670 - 2030 (Box 22)
  - 2031 - 2103 (Box 23)
  - 2104 - 2159 (Box 24)
  - 2160 - 2212 (Box 25)
  - 2213 - 2246 (Box 26)
  - 2247 - 2301 (Box 27)
  - 2302 - 2361 (Box 28)
  - 2362 - 2398 (Box 29)
  - 2399 - 2433 (Box 30)
  - 2433 - 2487 (Box 31)
  - 2488 - A2515 (Box 32)
  - A2516 - A2539 (Box 33)
  - A2540 - A2542 (Box 34)
  - A2543 - A2562 (Box 35)
  - A2562 - A2578 (Box 36)
  - A2578 - A2591 (Box 37)
  - A2591 - 2634B (Box 38)
  - 2635B - 2676C (Box 39)
  - 2676C - 2683C (Box 40)
  - 2683C - 2706D (Box 41)
  - 2706D - 2741D (Box 42)
  - 2742D - 2800E (Box 43)
  - 2801E - 2826F (Box 44)
  - 2813F - 2841F (Box 45)
  - 2842F - 2871F (Box 46)
  - 2872F - 2903G (Box 47)
  - 2904G - 2938H (Box 48)
  - 2938H - 2952H (Box 49)
  - 2953H - 2995I (Box 50)
  - 2996J - 3033J (Box 51)
  - 3934J - 3071K (Box 52)
  - 3072K - 3108L (Box 53)
  - 3108L - 3109L (Box 54)
  - 3110L - 3134L (Box 55)
  - 3135L - 3179M (Box 56)
  - 3180M - 3216N (Box 57)
  - 3217N - 3260O (Box 58)
  - 3261O - 73297O (Box 59)
  - 3298O - 3330P (Box 60)
  - 3331P - 3339P K (Box 61)
  - 3339P L - 3348P (Box 62)
  - 3349P - 3392Q (Box 63)
  - 3392Q - 3447R (Box 64)
  - 3448R - 3492R (Box 65)
  - 3493R - 3545S (Box 66)
  - 3546S - 3571T (Box 67)
  - 3572T - 3601T ABC (Box 68)
  - 3602T - 3656U (Box 69)
  - 3657U - 4695U (Box 70)
  - 3696U - 3731U (Box 71)
  - 3732U - 3777V (Box 72)
  - 3778V - 3826W (Box 73)
  - 3827W - 3851W (Box 74)
  - 3851WA - 3885W (Box 75)
  - 3886W - 3819X (Box 76)
  - 3920X - 3974X (Box 77)
  - 3975Y - 4011Y (Box 78)
  - 4012Y - 4037Y (Box 79)
  - 4038Y - 4080Z (Box 80)
  - 4081Z - 4121Z (Box 81)
  - 4122Z - 4172AA (Box 82)
  - 4173AA - 4217AA (Box 83)
  - 4218AA - 4261BB (Box 84)
  - 4262BB A&B - 4316BB (Box 85)
  - 4317BB - 4363CC (Box 86)
  - 4364CC - 4831CC (Box 87)